

MD JAHIR ALAM RAJU

Where ever go, go with all hearts

Highly-enthusiastic, and dedicated Lead Programmer with more than 4 years of experience in leading programming, development, enhancement and implementation of web and windows applications or software using Javascript technology or platform.

Expertise in Javascript, Java, Python, C++ and SQL coding, analyzing user requirements or specifications, software testing and debugging, code optimization and troubleshooting as well as possess excellent leadership, analytical, time-management, communication and problem-solving skills.

EXPERIENCE

Engineering Resource International —Lead Developer may 2018 - June 2019

- Leading a team of programmers and coordinating development, testing, debugging, and implementation of universal Javascript programs for various business or custom software according to user requirements and established coding.
- Liaising between management and IT personnel, including analysts, designers or software engineers to develop, implement, and deliver efficient, secure and scalable web and mobile based applications (globalrtis.com) for World Bank (IFC) which will store a big amount of data and analyzed related to garments factory sector.

Bitspeck Solutions — Software Engineer December 2017 - May 2018

- Stuffing all aspects of the application development operations, engineering and project architecture.
- Managing application development team and administrator of server management.
- Building a world class ecommerce platform (makzun.com) with help of team member using all the most latest technologies such as api-driven, universal js SPA (node, angular, redux, pwa), mysql, mongodb, elasticsearch, docker.
- Configure and maintain source code control and issue tracking systems using gitlab and asana and cloud server like digitalocean.



+880-1740618846 work.jahir@gmail.com jahir.me /jahir9991 @jahir9991

Skills & Competencies

Language:

Javascript, Python, Php, C#, C++, lava.

Framework & library:

Nodejs (Express, Sails, Mean), Laravel, .Net, Spring (Hibernate), Angular, Reactjs, Redux, Typescript, Socket.io, SignalR, Bootstrap, Antdesign,Typescript. Ionic,Flutter (mobile)

Database:

MySQL, PostgreSQL, Mongodb, Firebase,SQL Server, Rethinkdb, Elasticsearch, Algolia.

Tools:

Git , Trello, Asana, Webpack, Babel, Gulp, Composer, Npm, Maven, Bower, Sass, Jquery.

Development Method:

Rest Api, SPA(ssr & csr), Microservice, WebSocket, Caching, Load Balancer, JWT, Continuous Integration, PWA, Dockerization

Recently learning:

Python (Django), Scala, GraphQL Tensorflow.js.

AWARDS

AIUB CS FEST (2016) App contest, 1st rank

LANGUAGES

Bangla, English, Hindi (speaking)

Access to Information(PMO) — Software Engineer January 2017 - PRESENT

- Working on Bangladesh Govt's largest agriculture web-portal (krishi.gov.bd) using nodejs(express), mongodb and mysql(sequelize), jwt, socket.io (real-time) to make project api-driven and optimized.
- Developing and designing a fair trading ecommerce application called Noipunno with universal js stack (node, sails js, angular, redux, ant-design, jwt, mysql).
- Developing and designing a fair trading ecommerce application called Noipunno with universal js stack (node, sails js, angular, redux, ant-design, jwt, mysql).

Workspace Infotech — *Software Engineer* February 2016 - November 2017

- Worked in java(spring) with team to optimize and update realacquisitions.com 's system to fully api driven with microservice architecture and redesigned some database.
- Extended some feature in islamiqa.com with a php cms(question2answer), jquery and bootstrap.

Ennvisio Digital Private Ltd — Jr. Software Engineer May 2015 - February 2016

- Full stack development through some web technologies like php(laravel), js(jquery, nodejs, angularjs), mysql etc.
- Successfully completed some web project like ennvisiodigital.tech, Amarmistri.com, awamiportal.com.

EDUCATION

American International University Bangladesh, Dhaka

— BSc in Software Engineering Passing year - 2016

Chaumuhani Govt S A College, Noakhali

— *HSC* Passing year : 2011

Begumgonj Govt Pilot High School, Noakhali

— SSC Passing year: 2009

Personal Information

Father Badiul Alam

Mother Taj Nahar

Begum

Permanent Address Nahar Manzil, Mondolpara, Chaumuhani Begumgonj, Noakhali.

DOB 1 December,

1993

Blood Group

0+

Sex Male

Religion Islan

Marital Status

Unmarried

Nationality Bangladeshi

National ID 19937520707000082

Interest

Travelling, Googling, Attend programming seminar, Reading books, Learn new things .